Guide to the Ezra Pound Papers Addition
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Ezra Pound papers: addition
1862-1983
1960-1971
YCAL MSS 53
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
20.5
(46 boxes)
The Ezra Pound Papers Addition consists of material related to the life and career of the American poet Ezra Pound and includes correspondence, manuscripts, and a small quantity of personal papers. Correspondents include Homer and Isobel Pound, George Antheil, Basil Bunting, T. S. Eliot, James Laughlin, Marianne Moore, William Carlos Williams, and Henri Gaudier-Brzeska. Manuscripts inclue draft portions of The Cantos, autograph scores of Le Testament de Villon and Cavalcanti, and drafts of essays.
Pound, Ezra, 1885-1972
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Addition to the Pound Papers was received by Yale University in 1990 from Olga Rudge and the Ezra Pound Foundation.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Associated Materials
Ezra Pound Papers. YCAL MSS 43
EZRA POUND
A biographical sketch of Ezra Pound can be found in the finding aid for the Ezra Pound Papers, YCAL MSS 43.
Scope and Contents
The Ezra Pound Papers Addition consists of material related to the life and career of the American poet Ezra Pound received by the Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library after the processing of the Ezra Pound Papers acquired in 1973. The Addition consists of letters, manuscripts, photographs, and personal papers and memorabilia belonging to Pound. Materials in the collection (approximately twenty linear feet) span the years 1862 to 1983, with the bulk of the collection dated between 1960 and 1972.
The Ezra Pound Addition is divided into three series: I. Correspondence, II. Writings, and III. Personal Papers. Oversize material has been placed at the end of the collection.
Series I., Correspondence (Boxes 1-28), is arranged alphabetically by personal or institutional name and contains letters to and from Pound. (A list of files containing letters from Pound is included at the end of the DESCRIPTION OF THE PAPERS.)
A highlight of the collection is a series of nineteen letters from Pound to his parents, Homer and Isabel Pound, during his European study tour in 1906. Written from Madrid, Paris, and London, the letters describe Pound's impressions, studies, and writing and reveal much about his early thoughts and aspirations.
Later letters from Pound to numerous friends and acquaintances often reveal his thoughts on poetry (his own or others'), politics, economics, and other subjects. The file for Jane Lidderdale contains a brief typescript of Pound's recollections of Harriet Weaver and the Egoist, while several letters to Ethel Duncan comment on his own work and that of T. S. Eliot and others. A letter to the New Republic (May 10, 1930) gives Pound's estimate of modern misinterpretations of Rabelais, and a lengthy letter to Lawrence Pollinger (February 23, 1938) discusses his interest in musical composition.
An undated letter to a Dr. Mahr gives Pound's blunt views on German radio propaganda, and two letters in 1944 from an official with the German embassy in Italy invite Pound to visit Berlin and to participate in "our American-English broadcasts." Pound's letter to U. S. Attorney-General Francis Biddle on August 4, 1943 (included in several drafts) takes strong issue with his indictment for treason.
Among the prominent authors represented in the correspondence are Basil Bunting, Cyril Connolly, E. E. Cummings, T. S. Eliot, Hilda Doolittle (H. D.), Ernest Hemingway, James Joyce, Robert Lowell, Archibald MacLeish, Marianne Moore, Desmond O'Grady, and William Carlos Williams. Other figures connected with Pound's career include Margaret Anderson, George Antheil, Caresse Crosby, James Laughlin, Gian Carlo Menotti, and Giovanni Schweiller. Their letters to Pound often reveal much about their own writing or that of Pound and others.
T. S. Eliot wrote to Pound on a variety of subjects, both personal and professional. A letter of September 2, 1927 acknowledges Pound's influence on Eliot and other writers, while others comment on such figures as W. H. Auden and Lincoln Kirstein. A letter from Hemingway of July 22, 1933 speaks of fishing, patriotism, government bureaucracy, indebtedness to Pound, and the writing of The Sun Also Rises; another from 1926 analyzes Ford Madox Ford's novel No More Parades. E. E. Cummings's letter of August 8, 1962 comments briefly on Robert Graves, Norman Douglas, and others, while an undated letter from Mary Bernard (c. 1946) discusses Marianne Moore.
Letters from William Carlos Williams (1923-63) discuss both his own writing and that of Pound. His letter of November 26 (n.y.) describes a legal entanglement over one of his stories printed in New Masses; a letter of February 20 (n.y.) laments having to split time between writing and practicing medicine and announces his decision to remain in the United States; and a letter from 1948 critiques Eliot's play The Family Reunion.
Among many authors revealing their indebtedness to Pound are Robert Lowell, Archibald MacLeish, and W. S. Merwin. By far the most prolific correspondent among Pound's many publishers was James Laughlin of New Directions Press. His letters (1935-71) discuss not only Pound's publications but the work of many other major twentieth-century authors. The letters not only give details on the publications of Pound's texts, but they often comment indirectly on Pound's thoughts and reactions to printings, royalties, piracies, and other issues.
Among the most fascinating correspondence in the collection are a number of letters written by the noted sculptor Henri Gaudier-Brzeska in 1914-15 while serving in France in World War I. Although the letters say little about Gaudier-Brzeska's interrupted career, they comment on battles and graphically describe the uncomfortable, unstable life of the common soldier during the war.
Other individual letters deserve brief mention. A letter to Pound from Eva Hesse on January 17, 1951 discusses in some detail the political environment in post-war Germany, the American occupation, and German feelings toward the United States and Russia. Marshall McLuhan's letter (c. 1948) comments on what he calls the "complete prolitarianization of the middle classes." An undated letter from Viola Baxter Jordan (c. 1939?) mentions Pound's radio broadcasts from Italy, while several of her later letters discuss H.D. and her daughter Perdita.
In addition to Homer and Isabel Pound, other family correspondents include Dorothy Pound, Mary and Boris de Rachewiltz, and Pound's grandchildren Walter de Rachewiltz and Patrizia de Rachewiltz De Vroom. Among Pound's friends and acquaintances, the more prolific letter-writers include Renata Borgatti, Ethel Duncan, Ronald Duncan, Viola Baxter Jordan, Brigit Patmore, George Slavin, Marcella Spann, and Henry Swabey.
Placed at the end of this series are unidentified correspondents, fan mail, and incomplete drafts of letters by Pound.
Series II, Writings (Boxes 29-35), is divided into Books and Shorter Works and contains manuscripts of many of Pound's books, poems, essays, translations, musical scores, and miscellaneous writings, some with notes and other related material. Included are numerous holograph or typescript sections of the Cantos, often with Pound's corrections or annotations. The several musical scores (complete or fragmentary) document Pound's interest in music and the setting of poetry to music. Present are various holograph drafts of the scores of The Testament of François Villon ( Le Testament de Villon ) and Cavalcanti, as well as scores of shorter pieces. At the end of the series are Pound's random notes and notebooks on literary matters not related to a specific work.
Series III, Personal Papers (Boxes 36-43), is arranged alphabetically by subject group (Address Books, Legal Papers, Notes, etc.). Included in this series are biographical information, legal and financial papers, medical reports, news clippings, photographs, writings about Pound, writings of others, and miscellaneous items.
Oversize (Boxes 42-44) contains material from Writings and Personal Papers.
List of files with letters, cards, telegrams, or notes by Ezra Pound:
Agresti, Olivia Rossetti
Angleton, James
Bacigalupo Family
Barney, Natalie
Beckett, Samuel
Berry, John
Biddle, Francis
Bird, Otto
Borgatti, Renata
Bullock, Marie
Cadorin, Guido
Chigi-Saracin, Guido
Cookson, William
Curtis Brown, Ltd. (notes)
Dalliba-John, Kate
Davenport, Guy
Donoghue, D.
Duncan, Ethel
Duncan, Ronald
Du Sautoy, Peter
Ede, James
Eliot, T. S.
Equitable Trust Company
Favai, Gennaro
Goedel, Carl
H. D. (Hilda Doolittle)
Horne, Mr.
King, Robert
Laughlin, James
Lees, David
Library of Congress (L. Q. Mumford)
Life
Lippi, Simonetta
Littlefield, Lester
McDaniels, Walton
MacDiarmid, Hugh
Mapel, Ida B.
Mahr, Dr.
Mazziniani, Seminatori
Mead, Ellen and Henry
Mencken, H. L.
Menotti, Gian Carlo
Mezzasoma, F.
Monotti, Francesco
Museé National d'Art Moderne
New Republic
New York Herald
O'Grady, Desmond
Patmore, Brigit
Pearson, Norman Holmes
Polignac, Wineretta de
Pollinger, Lawrence
Prospettive
Raymond, Cl.
Ringer, Gordon (notes)
Ronsisvalle, Vanni
Roux, Dominique de
Sewanee Review
Singh, George
Slocum, John
Spender, Stephen
Sperandeo, Giussepina Cosco
Spoleto Festival
Stevens, C. F. Terrell
Strauss, Roger
Sullivan, J. P. (card)
Time
Von Leers, Professor
Wallace, Naomi
Walter, Susan
Winslow, Ann
Wolfe, Humbert (notes)
Wykes-Joyce, Max (notes)
Yates, Richard
American literature -- 20th Century; Fascism and literature; Imagist poetry; Music and literature; Music -- History and criticism; Poetry, Modern -- 20th Century; Social credit; World War, 1939-1945 -- Propaganda; H. D. (Hilda Doolittle), 1886-1961; Antheil, George, 1900-1959; Barnard, Mary; Barney, Natalie Clifford, 1877-1972; Bird, William, 1888-1963; Blackmur, R. P. (Richard P.), 1904-1965; Bunting, Basil, 1900-; Cavalcanti, Guido, -1300; Collignon, Raymonde; Connolly, Cyril, 1903-1974; Cornell, Julien D., 1910-; Crosby, Caresse, 1892-1970; Cummings, E. E. (Edward Estlin), 1894-1962; Cunard, Nancy, 1896-1965; Eliot, T. S. (Thomas Stearns), 1888-1965; Fitzgerald, Joan; Fletcher, John Gould, 1886-1950; Fuller, R. Buckminster (Richard Buckminster), 1895-1983; Gaudier-Brzeska, Henri, 1891-1915; Ginsberg, Allen, 1926-1997; Gourmont, Remy de, 1858-1915; Hartmann, Sadakichi, 1867-1944; Hemingway, Ernest, 1899-1961; Hesse, Eva; Joyce, James, 1882-1941; Kenner, Hugh; Laughlin, James, 1914-1997; Marinetti, F. T., 1876-1944; McAlmon, Robert, 1896-1956; McLuhan, Marshall, 1911-1980; Monroe, Harriet, 1860-1936; Moore, Marianne, 1887-1972; O'Grady, Desmond, 1935-; Pea, Enrico, 1881-1958; Pearson, Norman Holmes, 1909-1975; Pound, Dorothy; Pound, Ezra, 1885-1972; Quinn, Mary Bernetta, 1915-; Rodker, John, 1894-1955; Russell, Peter, 1921-2003; Scheiwiller, Giovanni, 1889-1965; Serly, Tibor, 1901-1978; Villa-Lobos, Heitor, 1887-1959; Williams, William Carlos, 1883-1963; Wolfe, Humbert, 1885-1940; Zukofsky, Louis, 1904-1978; Hound & Horn; New Directions Incorporated
- Correspondence, 1906-72; Series I; 11.25; (28 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Series I, Correspondence, is arranged alphabetically by surname and chronologically within files. Significant correspondents, files containing letters from Pound, and those with three or more letters have been given separate folders; others have been placed in "letter general" files.
  - "A" general, 1929-72 (Box 1, Folder 1-4)
  - Academy of American Poets, 1964-70 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Agresti, Olivia Rossetti, 1944-51 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Aldington, Richard, 1961 Mar 10 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Aldrich, Michael, 1966-67 (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
  - Alexander, Michael, 1962-66 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Amoral, José V., 1968 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - American Academy of Political and Social Science, 1940-71 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Analis, Demetrius, 1966-69 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Anderson, Margaret, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Angeli, Helen Rossetti, 1949 May 18 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Angleton, James J., 1941 Apr 2 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Antheil, George, 1927-33, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 17-18)
  - Aragon, Louis, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Arte Viva, 1965-66 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Awiszus, Sabine, 1967-71 (Box 1, Folder 21-22)
  - "B" general, 1928-72 (Box 2, Folder 23-32)
  - Bacigalupo family, 1964-69 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Bacon, Frank, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Barnard, Mary, 1965-67 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Barney, Natalie, 1925-68 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Bates, Margaret, 1965-72 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Beckett, Samuel (note from Pound) (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Bedford, Agnes, 1964 Aug 11 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Belgion, Montgomery, 1969-70 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Berenson, Mary, 1933 Nov 29 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Berrigan, Theodore, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Bevollmächtigte der Grossdeutschen Reiches bei Italienschen Regierung, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Biddle, Francis (Attorney General of the United States), 1943 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Bird, William, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    Related Archival Materials note
    See also: Three Mountain Press, Box 22, folder 509
  - Blackburn, Paul, 1964-71 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Blackmur, R. P., 1927, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Boni and Liveright, Publishers, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Borgatti, Renata, 1937-48, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 49-50)
  - Bowen, Stella, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Bridson, Geoffrey, 1959 Nov 20 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - British Broadcasting Corporation (British Broadcasting System), 1931-64 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Bullock, Marie, 1963, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Bunting, Basil, 1964-71 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Burnett, Whit
    See: This Is My Best, Box 22, folder 508
  - "C" general, 1924-72 (Box 3, Folder 56-64)
  - C. B. S. News, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Cadorin, Guido, 1970-71, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 66-67)
  - Caico, Lina, 1939-48 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Cambon, Glauco, 1968 Nov 1 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Canadian Broadcasting Corporation, 1970 Feb 27 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Canfield, Cass, 1969 Sep 10 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Carnevali, Emanuel, [1930?] (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Carpanini, Ferdinando, 1966-71 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Castagneto, Umberto, 1969-70 (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Chamberlin, Frederick, 1926 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Chigi-Saracini, Guido, [1941?] (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Chute, Desmond, [1928] (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Cini, Vittorio, 1965-71 (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Civis, Euro, 1963-67 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Clemens, Cyril, 1962-72 (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Collignon, Raymonde, 1924-64 (Box 4, Folder 81)
  - Empty folder (Box 4, Folder 82)
  - Columbia University (Writing Program), 1967-71 (Box 4, Folder 83)
  - Connolly, Cyril, 1969-71 (Box 4, Folder 84)
    See also: William Cookson, Box 4, folder 86
  - Consulate General of the United States of America, 1969 Feb 6 (Box 4, Folder 85)
  - Cookson, William, 1962-72, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 86-88)
  - Corey, Daniel, 1965 Jul 25 (Box 4, Folder 89)
  - Cornell, Julian, 1965, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 90)
  - Cosco, Guiseppine Sperandeo
    See: Sperandeo Cosco, Box 22, folder 485
  - Cournos, John, 1925 Jan 24 (Box 4, Folder 91)
  - Empty folder (Box 4, Folder 92)
  - Creeley, Robert (Buffalo Arts Festival), 1967 Jul 27 (Box 4, Folder 93)
  - Criterion
    See: T. S. Eliot, Box 5, folder 125
  - Crosby, Caresse, 1965-69, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 94)
  - Cummings, E. E., 1946, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 95)
  - Cunard, Nancy (with letter from Hugh Ford), 1965, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 96)
    See also: Hours Press, Box 8, folder 189
  - Curtis Brown, Ltd., 1930-64 (Box 4, Folder 97)
  - "D" general, 1930-72 (Box 4, Folder 98-103)
  - Dadone, Ugo, 1961-63 (Box 4, Folder 104)
  - Dalliba-John, Katherine (Ramooth), 1927-36 (Box 4, Folder 105)
  - Davenport, Guy, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 106)
  - Davies, Ingrid, 1969-70 (Box 4, Folder 107)
  - Dazzi, Manlio Torquato ("Torq"), 1928-67 (Box 4, Folder 108)
  - Dewey, Davis R., 1940 Jun 6 (Box 4, Folder 109)
  - The Dial, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 110)
  - Dickey, R. P., 1964-68 (Box 4, Folder 111)
  - Dolmetsch Foundation, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 112)
  - Donoghue, D., n.d. (Box 4, Folder 113)
  - Doolittle, Hilda
    See: H. D., Box 8, folder 179
  - Drummond, Fifi Drummond, John, 1965, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 114)
  - Dudek, Louis, 1961-69 (Box 5, Folder 115)
  - Duncan, Ethel, 1933-52 (Box 5, Folder 116)
  - Duncan, Ronald, 1947-70, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 117)
  - Duran, Alex Duran, Vera, 1963-69 (Box 5, Folder 118)
  - Du Sautoy, Peter (Faber and Faber), 1965-71 (Box 5, Folder 119)
  - "E" general, 1928-72 (Box 5, Folder 120-21)
  - East Texas State University, 1969, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 122)
  - Easton, Alexander, 1965-66 (Box 5, Folder 123)
  - Ede, James, 1965-68 (Box 5, Folder 124)
  - Eliot, T. S. ( Criterion ), 1927-65 (Box 5, Folder 125)
  - Ellmann, Richard, 1964 May 20 (Box 5, Folder 126)
  - Emery, Clark, 1967 Aug 17 (Box 5, Folder 127)
  - England, Robert, 1966-70 (Box 5, Folder 128)
  - The English Journal, 1930 Jun 27 (Box 5, Folder 129)
  - Equitable Trust Company, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 130)
  - Espey, John, 1965 Dec 28 (Box 5, Folder 131)
  - Esquire, 1962-68 (Box 5, Folder 132)
  - "F" general, 1932-72 (Box 5, Folder 133-37)
  - Faber and Faber, 1965-71 (Box 6, Folder 138)
    See also: T. S. Eliot and Peter Du Sautoy, Box 5, folder 125
  - Fang, Paul, 1963-70 (Box 6, Folder 139)
  - Farrell, Patric, 1965-70, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 140)
  - Fascio di Londra, 1930 Dec 27 (Box 6, Folder 141)
  - Fasolo, Ugo, 1965-71 (Box 6, Folder 142)
  - Favai, Gennaro, 1935 Dec 23 (Box 6, Folder 143)
  - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence, 1963 Jan 14 (Box 6, Folder 144)
  - Firebird Films, 1967-68 (Box 6, Folder 145)
  - Fischer, Walther, 1965-71 (Box 6, Folder 146)
  - Fitzgerald, Joan, 1963-71 (Box 6, Folder 147)
  - Fitzgerald, Robert Fitzgerald, Sally, 1971 Dec 30 (Box 6, Folder 148)
  - Fletcher, John Gould, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 149)
  - Folger Shakespeare Library, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 150)
  - Fondazione Giorgio Cini, 1964-72 (Box 6, Folder 151)
  - Ford, Ford Madox, 1933 Jul 7 (Box 6, Folder 152)
  - Foster, Jeanne, 1963-69 (Box 6, Folder 153)
  - Fox, Douglas, 1933 Dec 27 (Box 6, Folder 154)
  - Fuller, Buckminster, 1971, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 155)
  - Furniss, Robert, 1962-70 (Box 6, Folder 156)
  - "G" general, 1929-72, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 157-62)
  - Garland, Patrick
    See: Poetry Book Society, Box 14, folder 348
  - Gaudier-Brzeska, Henri, 1914-15, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 163)
  - Gelpi, Albert, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 164)
  - Ginsberg, Allen, 1967, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 165)
  - Giovannini, Giovanni, 1963-72 (Box 7, Folder 166)
  - Goacher, Denis, 1955-68 (Box 7, Folder 167)
  - Goedel, Carl, 1966-68 (Box 7, Folder 168)
  - Gould, Joseph, 1930 (Box 7, Folder 169)
  - Gourmont, Remy de, 1915 Jun 13 (Box 7, Folder 170)
  - "H" general, 1928-72 (Box 7, Folder 171-72)
  - "H" general, 1928-72 (Box 8, Folder 173-78)
  - H. D. (Hilda Doolittle Aldington), 1911-53, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 179)
  - Hall, Donald (with letter from Arthur V. Moore), 1963 (Box 8, Folder 180)
  - Hardison, O. B.
    See: Folger Shakespeare Library, Box 6, folder 150
  - Hartmann, Sadikichi (with related correspondence), 1970 (Box 8, Folder 181)
  - Hatfield, Mark, 1969 Jan 17 (Box 8, Folder 182)
  - Hemingway, Ernest Hemingway, Mary, 1926-65, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 183)
  - L'Herne
    See: Dominique de Roux, Box 15, folder 386
  - Hesse, Eva, 1951-69, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 184)
  - Horne (?), Mr., n.d. (Box 8, Folder 185)
  - Horton, T. David, 1969-72 (Box 8, Folder 186-87)
  - Hound and Horn, 1930 (Box 8, Folder 188)
    See also: R. P. Blackmur, Box 2, folder 47
  - Hours Press, 1930, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 189)
  - Howe, Marvine ( New York Times ), 1962-71 (Box 8, Folder 190)
  - The Hudson Review, 1965-68 (Box 8, Folder 191)
  - Hughes, Ted
  - Empty folder (Box 8, Folder 192)
  - Hutchins, Patricia, 1962-68 (Box 8, Folder 193)
  - Hzyan, R. Y., 1966 (Box 8, Folder 194)
  - "I" general, 1939-72 (Box 8, Folder 195)
  - International Platform Society, 1964-69 (Box 8, Folder 196)
  - Ivancich, Gianfranco Ivancich, Irina, 1961-70, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 197-98)
  - "J" general, 1965-71, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 199-201)
  - The Japan Times and Mail (Box 9, Folder 202)
  - Jordan, Viola Baxter Jordan, Conrad Baxter, 1939-72 (Box 9, Folder 203)
  - Joyce Symposium, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 204)
  - Joyce, Lucia, 1969-72 (Box 9, Folder 205)
  - "K" general, 1928-72 (Box 9, Folder 206-09)
  - Kasper, John, 1952-62 (Box 9, Folder 210)
  - Kavka, Jerome, 1969 Apr 26 (Box 9, Folder 211)
  - Kenner, Hugh, 1952-64, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 212-13)
  - King, Robert, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 214)
  - Kirkpatrick, Heinz A., 1968-70 (Box 9, Folder 215)
  - Kirstein, Lincoln
    See: Hound and Horn, Box 8, folder 188
  - Knox, George
    See: Sadikichi Hartmann, Box 8, folder 181
  - Kodama, Sanchide, 1962-68 (Box 9, Folder 216-17)
  - Korshoon, Ivan, 1964 Sep 20 (Box 9, Folder 218)
  - "L" general, 1929-72 (Box 10, Folder 219-25)
  - Laughlin, James, 1950-70, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 226-34)
  - Lawton, Harry
  - Lees, David, 1966, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 235)
  - Library of Congress, 1939, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 236)
  - Lidderdale, Jane, 1962-63 (Box 10, Folder 237)
  - Life, 1963-64, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 238)
  - Lilienfield, V.
    See: Bevollmöchtigte des Grossdeutschen Reiches, Box 2, folder 43
  - Lippi, Simonetta, 1966-70, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 239)
  - The Listener
    See: British Broadcasting Corporation, Box 2, folder 53
  - Littlefield, Lester, 1947-72 (Box 10, Folder 240)
  - Lowell, Robert, 1963-67 (Box 10, Folder 241)
  - Lucas, John, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 242)
  - Lyttle, Andrew
    See: Sewanee Review, Box 17, folder 423
  - "M" general, 1931-72 (Box 11, Folder 243-52)
  - McAlmon, Robert, 1930, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 253)
  - McDaniels, Walton, 1965, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 254)
  - MacDiarmid, Hugh (with related correspondence), 1966-71 (Box 11, Folder 255-56)
  - MacDonald, Dwight, 1930 Apr 27 (Box 11, Folder 257)
  - MacGregor, Robert, 1954 Jan 28 (Box 11, Folder 258)
  - MacLeish, Archibald, 1962, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 259)
  - MacLeod, Joseph Gordon, 1930-33 (Box 11, Folder 260)
  - MacLeod, Norman, 1930 Apr 25 (Box 11, Folder 261)
  - McNaughton, William, 1964, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 262)
  - MacShane, Frank
    See: Columbia University, Box 4, folder 83
  - Maitland, Mary Maitland, Robert (with related correspondence), [1926, 1931] (Box 11, Folder 263-64)
  - Malipiero, ? (telegram from Pound) (Box 11, Folder 265)
  - Manfredi, Antonio, 1956, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 266)
  - Mangan, Sherry, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 267)
  - Mangione, Laura, 1969, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 268)
  - Mapel, Ida Bigler, 1941, 1947 (Box 11, Folder 269)
  - Marcher Family, 1932-34, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 270)
  - Mardersteig, Giovanni, 1963 Mar 13 (Box 12, Folder 271)
  - Marh, Dr., n.d. (Box 12, Folder 272)
  - Marinetti, F. T. (with "Hella Casa Gianca"), 1933 Feb 25 (?) (Box 12, Folder 273)
  - M'Arte, 1970-71 (Box 12, Folder 274)
  - Martell, Charles Martell, Nancy, 1964-69 (Box 12, Folder 275)
  - Martin, Herbert Woodward, 1972, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 276)
  - Martinelli, Sherri, 1962-69 (Box 12, Folder 277-78)
  - Matz, Charles, 1965-69 (Box 12, Folder 279)
  - Mazziniani, Seminatori (with enclosure), 1943 Nov 4 (Box 12, Folder 280)
  - Meacham, Harry M., 1962-66 (Box 12, Folder 281)
  - Mead, Ellen W. Mead, Henry, 1951-69 (Box 12, Folder 282)
  - Meeker, Junius D., 1969 Jun 10 (Box 12, Folder 283)
  - Mencken, H. L., 1939 May 11 (Box 12, Folder 284)
  - Menotti, Gian Carlo, 1960-70, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 285)
  - Merchant, W. Moelwyn, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 286)
  - Merwin, W. S., 1972 Jul 15 (Box 12, Folder 287)
  - Mezzasoma, F., 1945 (?) Mar 28 (Box 12, Folder 288)
  - Miller, Henry, 1970 May 19 (Box 12, Folder 289)
  - Milmore, John, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 290)
  - Ministro della Cultura Populare, 1941-44 (Box 12, Folder 291)
  - Mondadori, Arnaldo, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 292)